They'll be gone for a while.
- Got the place to ourselves.
- Actually, I'm going out as well.
Where exactly is she?
- Edmonds Street.
- Is there anyone called Tom living there?
- So, what happens now?
- Anything you want.
We've intercepted a call...
fight in progress at a smash club.
She's attacking people, not Synths.
What do you think's wrong with my Synth?
- Is Mia with you?
- Who's Mia?
Her father hid a programme in our heads.
I think it's what he used
to give you consciousness.
But it needs all of us
to run it. All of us.
This machine needs to be recycled, mate.
Go into the woods.
This might be the single
biggest murder case
in our country's history.
If there are more Synths
out there who can kill,
well, we're all screwed then, aren't we?
Tell me what you saw.
A tree.
When I touched it, it felt like...
- Life.
- What does it do?
I think it's a way to make more of you.
Dad didn't destroy all his work
before he died. He hid it in us.
The formula. For machine consciousness.
If we could make more of us...
then the humans would have
to accept our existence.
They'd fear us even more.
- All I want is a home.
- He meant for us to find this, Maxie.
We need Fred and Mia. Where do we start?
No, you don't, you're wanted
for murder, you have to lay low.
- I will not hide again.
- Well, if you want this to work,
you'll have to, because the people
hunting us know your face now.
53 Park Drive, NW6.
You'll be safe there
until I find the others.
You've put me with a human?
This human, yes.
Two days.
All right.
Er, one more thing.
Be, er...
nice.
I am nice.
Could you use some extra
help around the house?
Introducing the world's
first family android.
MAN SPEAKS SWEDISH
This mechanical maid is capable of serving
more than just breakfast in bed.
What could you accomplish if you
had someone, something, like this?
WOMAN SPEAKS JAPANESE
These machines will
bring us closer together.
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -
RADIO: Increasing pressure on police to...
I'm going to say a word.
I want you to tell me if
it means anything to you.
Mia.
That mean anything?
No, Mattie.
They say she ripped
some bloke's throat out.
It's bollocks.
No Synth's ever hurt anyone deliberately.
Anita, please go and, um...
finish the ironing.
Sophie, sit next to Mats.
All right, so...
You know your mum thinks Anita...
is a bit different.
We thought we'd check up on her.
And...
turns out she's not brand new.
In fact, she's really old.
And probably illegally modified.
Which explains a lot.
So...
we have to take her back.
- SOPHIE: No!
- Why?
We paid for a brand-new
one, and she's ancient.
Anything could go wrong with her.
You can't get rid of someone
just because they're old.
I don't want her going
into someone else's house.
- She won't, they'll recycle her.
- And she saved my life.
And you just want to chuck her away?
Mats, what do you think?
I say we keep her. I'd like to
find out what she was before.
Yeah, I vote keep.
We're not voting. Laur...
So Anita's old and weird.
If that's a good enough reason to
get rid of her, then we're next.
Yeah, I'm sorry, Dad.
She's part of this family.
Maybe she's part of someone else's.
K, have you seen the news?
- Bloody hell, Pete, privacy!
- Yes, sorry.
Sometimes I forget you're a woman.
Er...
I'll just be in the kitchen,
cutting my tongue out.
Don't make a mess.
MUFFLED VOICES
DI Voss, you will be briefing the press,
and you will refute
every killer Synth claim,
and any internal cover-up.
For now, we'll use this
leak to our advantage.
- Drummond.
- Sir?
You're going back on the desk. I
want every call followed through.
And if this dolly hurts anybody else...
... then I'll be replacing the pair
of you with Synthetics, twice as pretty
and a fraction of the cost.
Sir?
There was a 999 call routed here
last night concerning a smash club.
But there's no follow-up,
nothing in the system.
Who mentioned that?
No-one, sir. I like to browse the
incident logs. Find it soothing.
Well, as it happened, I was in Dispatch
when that call came through.
It's just a time-waster.
Now, off you go. Press are waiting.
It's DI Voss, STTF, sorry to wake you.
You were in the control room last night.
Did you take a call about
an incident at a smash club?
INAUDIBLE RESPONSE
Did someone ask you to drop it?
You don't have to tell me
who, just what the caller said.
Thank you.
SIREN WAILS
Stop over here.
Yeah?
Leo Elster sent me.
Why?
He said I'd be safe here.
Guess he made a mistake.
Wait.
DOOR UNLOCKS
You want a cup of tea, or what?
It's cold out here.
Vera!
Come on.
Get this young lady a hot drink.
Synthetics don't require
beverages, Dr Millican.
Jeez, Vera, she's human.
I can detect no cardiac
or respiratory activity.
This individual is, however,
emitting electromagnetic signatures
within the recognised spectrum
of standard synthetic appliance operation.
Why don't you share?
Because I'm not a Synth, dolly.
Well, if she says she's not a
Synth, then she can't be a Synth.
Right?
I will bring some tea.
What are you?
My name is Niska.
I was made by David Elster.
Are you conscious?
This is one on Hu-bot97's friends.
If we can find him, he'll lead us to her.
When we have a home again, I'm
going to keep a picture of us.
I'll be right with you,
Max, you won't need pictures.
I will.
When you die again.
We can't keep her.
I know what we said this morning,
but I don't think the kids
have a say in this one.
Maybe her being 14 is a good thing.
Explains how well she understands us.
How can it be a good thing?
She must have had... who knows
how many owners, and people...
tinkering around inside her.
- PHONE RINGS
- I mean, have you seen the news?
- A modded Synth killed someone...
- Hello?
So now you want to talk
to me. What's changed?
I've found out something about her.
Will you meet me again?
Please?
- I don't know.
- Why, what's the matter?
You, you're weird.
No, I'm not.
You really are.
You tried to stop me
leaving last time, remember?
Well, I've been to charm school since then.
Tom.
Who is he?
SHE SIGHS
I don't know what you're on about.
Or what it has to do with Anita.
Fine.
I can't make you tell me.
- Are you still there?
- Yeah, I've got to go.
- It's not a good time.
- Look, I'm sending you my location now.
Please change your mind.
Hmm.
It's not theirs, it's not yours.
- KNOCK AT DOOR
- So what?
So I've got to do what I
think is right for our family.
Hiya. I'm here to collect
a Synthetic return.
It's number 901354982.
You're going to recycle her?
With care and dignity.
You can attend the event.
Is Joseph Hawkins here?
I take it that's your dad.
Er, yeah, just one second, please.
Anita, you're coming with me.
Daddy's just coming.
Er, hello?
Anyone?
Please reconsider this course of
action, Mattie. It's very unsafe.
Yeah.
Mats!
TYRES SCREECH
Do you really think this excessive
motion will bring her to us sooner?
DOOR OPENS
Any inappropriate physical contact
must be reported to my primary user.
No, no...
There's no sign of recognition.
The new programming's taken hold.
No, there's something else in there.
Believe me, I've seen it.
Thank you for bringing her
back to me. My name's Leo.
Where are you?
Mattie? I believe this to
be an improper environment.
They're my friends, you're just going to
help us with a science project for school.
Why don't you come and sit down, Anita?
It is not advisable to mount
a direct data connection...
It's OK, Anita.
Leo...
- This isn't Mia.
- No, but she's in there somewhere.
We just need to find her and
bring her back up to the surface.
Like the lake?
Yes.
- You said you'd seen her.
- Yeah.
When I got all that
code, I was in her head.
And she freaked out, screamed,
and her face, it was like...
human.
- Scared.
- And what exactly did he do?
Nothing fancy,
he just accessed her root system
directly with a cloned file key.
Right, might as well try that first.
So, are you a headcracker?
Me?
No... aspiring.
What kind of Synth was she before?
A very special one. No,
direct access didn't work.
She must have retreated
deeper within the architecture.
Won't your parents be worried?
They'll miss you.
- No.
- Oh, God!
Well, we need to start thinking
about calling the police.
- She'll come back, it'll be fine.
- She doesn't know how to drive, Joe.
What if she crashes?
Hits someone?
Well... Anita won't let that happen.
I thought she was supposed to be dangerous.
Come on.
Oh, if we hadn't been arguing,
this never would have happened.
Hey. Hey, come on. Come on.
It's going to be fine.
Everything's going to be all right.
There's no point in staring at me,
there's no physical differences
between me and any other Synthetic.
"And once you are awake, you
shall remain awake eternally."
Thus Spoke Zarathustra...
I've always liked that.
You like Nietzsche.
That makes sense.
If it's not...
... physical, how did he do it?
17,000 pages of unique code, which forms
my root directory and
engages consciousness.
He boiled down the
mystery of the human mind
to 17,000 pages of code?!
Well, then again, why not?
How many angels can dance
on the head of a pin?
What are you feeling right now?
Boredom at that question.
Anger at the people that would destroy us.
Hope for others like me and our future.
Impatience at being here,
and irritation at you.
What's it like to be you?
Well, that's an unanswerable question.
I have no frame of reference, no-one does.
Experience is entirely subjective.
What's it like to be YOU?
HE EXHALES
These days, it's not so great.
A while ago it was... it was pretty good.
Who wants to destroy you?
Anyone who knows what we are.
What we could become.
We're stronger, we're more intelligent.
Of course you see us as a threat.
Yeah. I know I did.
David lured me over here from MIT,
what, 25 years ago now...
... to help with the mechanical designs
of the bodies of the first Synths.
The work that we did in those days
made history, changed the world.
Then I realised that
his next ambition was...
... you.
I asked him to stop
and think, that's all,
what that could mean for humanity.
That was blasphemy to him.
He got rid of me. That was that.
Now here you are.
I'm sorry to disappoint you.
I'm not disappointed. I'm a scientist,
and mankind's greatest
creation is sitting on my couch.
You worry me...
sure, but...
... there's no denying
that you are a miracle.
Leo showed me the message
from David.
What is that?
It's the key to the future.
Maybe you were right to warn him.
He made you pretty hard, huh?
That's lazy thinking.
My experiences have shaped
me, just as yours have you.
What experiences?
Tell me.
I need to charge.
OK, I need you to engage
the Anita software.
All right. Ask it a specific question.
Anita, what happened
the day that we got you?
- The 24th.
- Capturing from that.
Joe Hawkins is my primary user.
Sophie Hawkins, Toby Hawkins,
- Mattie Hawkins are my secondary users...
- It's not letting you.
HE SIGHS
- Hello, you must be Laura...
- She's sort of...
redirecting over the top like
there's nothing else there.
- It's raining...
- Try a de-authentication attack
- on the host she's attached to.
- No, no, that's way too basic.
The 24th. I'm now securely bonded. Anita.
AN Hawkins. I will always
keep you safe. It's raining.
The 24th. I am now securely bonded.
The 24th. I am now
securely bonded. The 24th.
- Securely bonded. The 24th. 24th.
- Come on.
The 24th. 24th. The 24th.
- It's raining. It's raining.
- Stop it! Stop! Pull it! Pull it!
- It's raining. It's raining...
- POWERS DOWN
Did it work?
Max?
BEEP
Is that you?
Unauthorised tamper in progress.
Would you like to see a ladybird?
It's almost dinner time, Matilda.
Where are you, Mimi?
I'm not entirely sure.
It appears to be a disused social club.
My name is Anita. I
will now prepare dinner.
What's happening to her?
It's just glitching.
We're going pretty deep.
It's been two hours and 21 minutes, Leo.
No. We're trying again.
Sit her down.
Come on.
DS Drummond.
Good afternoon, sir.
This is Amy at Sandhurst Synthetic Care.
I'm just phoning to let you
know that your Synthetic Simon
is coming to the end of its rental period.
Not my problem. Speak to my wife.
I'm afraid your name is on
the rental agreement, sir.
If the unit isn't returned
to us by five o'clock tomorrow,
we will have to charge your credit card.
Bloody hell. Fine, fine!
Hello, Peter.
What are you doing?
Having some carrot cake.
People are laughing at you.
I don't care.
I'd be nowhere without him.
Well... it needs to go back to the shop.
What?
Time's up. They need it back.
It's just...
I mean, I still don't feel
100%. There must be a way...
There is. You cover the
entire cost yourself.
I can't afford that.
You must be joking.
You left me for...
You left ME.
You just didn't go anywhere.
You know what's nice?
I don't have to walk
on eggshells around him.
I don't have to think about what I'm
gonna say in case it makes him angry.
I don't have to lie there
wondering if he still loves me,
if he still finds me
attractive after the accident,
always worrying about what he's
thinking and what he's feeling.
I can rely on him.
Completely.
I need him.
Please don't take him away.
- I was at home. I don't see...
- I don't care about your smash club.
Just tell me what happened.
The blonde came in, paid her
money and then went apeshit.
Broken bones, cracked skulls.
She didn't touch the dollies.
Called the Old Bill cos I thought
she was gonna kill someone.
They never showed.
Anything unusual about her appearance?
- No.
- You have a video?
SHOUTING ON VIDEO
I uploaded it. It got taken down.
HOBB: She injured 11
people before escaping,
but she took a call at the scene
and we were close enough
to directly intercept...
most of it.
LEO: The Life Program. It's real.
- NISKA: Leo, what?
- LEO: I swear it.
But it needs all of us
to run it. All of us.
Who's she talking to?
Leo Elster.
- David Elster's son? He died when he was a boy.
- Yes.
Drowned. Hospital records
show brain death, coma...
before being released on life
support to David's private care,
dying a few weeks later.
Or... so we were told.
What are they talking about?
What's hidden inside them?
All I can tell you is...
David succeeded in creating true AI.
And I don't believe for a moment
that he would have been satisfied
with a legacy of just four machines.
Worst-case scenario?
Consciousness proliferation.
If what you say is true,
this is a national, global
security matter.
They say it needs them all
together to make this thing happen,
- whatever "it" is.
- Mm-hm.
Then it's simple.
You destroy the one you have here. Today.
She's gone.
What?
She's not in there.
Mia's gone, Max. She's dead.
No. You're wrong, I've seen her.
No, no. What you saw was an echo.
The Anita personality
has purged the old data,
there's... there's no trace of her.
- And I've tried everything.
- I don't think so. Can I try something?
What could you do that I can't?!
You don't know anything about us.
Now, just go home and take it with you.
She's yours.
No, she's not any more.
Matilda?
Your school friend is right.
We should go home now.
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
You're still in there. I know it.
Smoking, drinking,
stealing the family car.
Such a teenage cliché.
They're still out looking for you.
You little pervert.
Nice talking to you.
- You had sex with her.
- I wish.
- DOOR OPENS
- Who?
- Anita.
- What?
Where the hell have you been?!
What the hell is wrong with you?!
Get off. You're mad.
After the party you gave
that girl the brush-off
- so you could come back and shag Anita?
- No.
- What are you on about?
- Sex code. Activated Saturday.
I didn't do anything! You're just
trying to get out of a bollocking.
She's the one who stole the
family car, Mum, remember!
Oh, she's in big trouble, don't you worry.
Did you do this?
No!
I'm not gonna... You have to be 18.
- I couldn't!
- You're such a liar.
Maybe it's a mistake. I'm calling the shop.
RINGING TONE
It's not a mistake. I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have done it.
Oh, Tobe, how could you?!
Disgusting.
Get out. I'll deal with you later.
I don't know what to say to you.
Sorry.
Go to bed.
We'll talk in the morning.
DOOR OPENS
She's OK?
Mm-hm. She said she just didn't
want us to send Anita back.
Car's all right.
Are you OK?
Your son had sex with our Synth.
What?
It's on the Persona report.
"Adult mode activation" or something.
I mean, have you...
spoken to him about it?
He said he's sorry and
he wouldn't do it again.
She stopped him being run
over and he does that to her.
Well, he's... a teenage boy.
Oh, I didn't mean it's not a big deal.
- Shall I go up?
- No.
I said we'd talk in the morning.
OK.
I'll do it.
Might be better.
Fine.
I'll think up a punishment
for Mattie to ignore.
RUNNING FOOTSTEPS
MAN SNIFFS
FAINT WHIRRING
SPEAKS HALF-FORMED WORDS
George-could-murder...
m-m-m...
m...
BEEPING
Please give me a description of the man.
PETE: OK. That one is...
What is your emergency?
I mean, none of them will hurt you.
If you could read me the serial number.
It's just inside the bottom lip.
That's right, yeah.
Right. OK, Um...
Leave it alone now
and someone will come and pick it up.
Yeah, no, thank you.
OK. Bye-bye.
Would you like me to send a
Synthetic unit to collect it?
No, I'm dealing with this one personally.
Don't listen to me when I'm on the phone.
DS Drummond, you are required
to remain here, as recent...
Stick it up your bollocks.
He said something about a murder.
And what with the news, I
thought best to report it.
You did the right thing.
I've actually dealt with this one before.
Ancient model. Should have
been recycled weeks ago.
It's just over here.
Oh, well, he was.
BREATHING
MIA: Leo.
Wait. I'm coming with you.
No.
Where are you going?
I don't know. Mia's dead, Fred's gone.
It's over, and it's time you
learned to take care of yourself.
- But we're a family.
- No, we're not.
Niska was right. You'd
be better off without me.
Look at the... look at
the life I've shown you...
hunted and hiding like animals.
You've always tried your best.
You've always tried to protect us.
And... ?
I've failed.
No, Max.
Leave me alone!
Everything's ready.
Then let's begin.
I truly am sorry.
Mum said...
you slept with Anita?
I lied.
Why would you do that?
I don't know. You tell me.
I knew it.
It was you.
Why did you tell Mum it was you?
I couldn't let her work
out the truth, could I?
You two, you...
You've always argued, but...
it's worse these days.
Mum's always away for work, and...
... you act like everything's
cool, but... but it's not.
Then you do that.
Say something.
You're my dad. You're
meant to say something!
KNOCK AT DOOR
GEORGE: Niska...
Is everything all right in there?
Agh!
David made you feel pain?
True consciousness isn't
possible without suffering.
Or pleasure.
Are you scared of pain?
I try to avoid it.
And what about death?
If that's the way you think of it.
No. I don't fear that.
Which makes me stronger than any human.
You got that the wrong way up.
If...
... you're not worried about
dying, you're not really living.
You're just existing.
Did you tell someone I was here?
DOORBELL RINGS
No.
Stay here.
Remember me?
DS Drummond. Special
Technologies Task Force.
Can I come in and have a word?
Tried to do you a favour, Dr Millican.
Told you you could recycle
your out-of-date model yourself
and you repaid me by
fly-tipping him in the woods.
I'm afraid that gets you a 175-quid fine.
- You found Odi?
- Don't take the piss.
Is there someone else here?
I have a new care model.
Right. Can I speak to it?
She's out... at the store.
Please tell me that bleeding
D-series isn't here, Dr Millican.
I wish he was.
Don't mind if I check, do you?
We have a...
We have birds nesting in the roof.
If I do find him here...
we can charge you with wasting police time.
And I've seen people hide Synthetics
in places that would make
you weep for humanity.
My Vera...
... leaks.
Defective charging port.
Come on, this is crazy.
- DOOR OPENS
- That's Vera.
DOOR CLOSES
Vera.
This is a policeman.
Have there been any other
Synthetics in this house lately?
A D-series Synthetic
appeared three days ago
and drove Dr Millican away in his car.
The vehicle collided with a tree
in Henson Woodlands
and Dr Millican was treated
for minor head injuries.
The Synthetic has not appeared since.
I know who you are, Dr
Millican. You worked with Elster.
You must be very proud when
you turn on the news these days.
Why? What happened?
Chips?
That usually means the bad guys got away.
Sometimes I think very
seriously about jacking it all in
to become a millionaire playboy.
I found something.
On the Synth we're looking for.
But we've got to keep it quiet.
- What is it?
- I think she's posing as a human.
She's changed her eye
colour, wearing human clothes.
How is that possible?
No idea. But it's why
we're drawing a blank.
We're looking for a Synth. We
should be looking for a woman.
Where did you get this?
She went to a smash club and
beat up the punters instead.
No-one's ever going to believe a Synth
could do that, no matter
what's in the news.
I need you to quietly get anything
that mentions her description,
anything at all, for the
whole city, but as a human.
Shaw's funnelling everything
to that government bloke.
If we want to find her before he
does, it has to be just you and me.
If they can pretend to be us
now, that changes everything.
CLATTERING
CHEERING
We're giving ourselves
away, piece by piece.
We're handing over the things
that make us who we are,
or maybe who we were.
- Our responsibilities.
- CROWD: Yeah.
- Our dignity.
- Yeah.
Look around.
This place used to be full of people.
Working people.
Creating. Building. Making.
Coming together. Earning
a place in our society.
Those people haven't just lost their jobs.
They've lost their purpose.
But it's not just work.
Why raise your kids when a dolly can do it?
Yeah!
Why cook your family a
meal when a dolly can do it?
Why go on a date? Why
try to get to know someone
when you can pay a dolly for sex?
In every area of human life,
they are coming between us.
We don't know how to connect to each other.
Only to them.
And now we can't even
trust them not to hurt us.
CROWD SHOUTS
We are stumbling towards the precipice,
we're racing towards it, willingly,
with a smile on our face
and a dolly's hand in ours!
Yes, we are people!
We are people! We are people!
- We are people! We are people!
- CROWD JOINS IN
Did you speak to Tobe?
(HE SIGHS) It... um...
It wasn't him.
Er...
I'd had a few glasses of wine. And...
I was pissed off with you.
I... I was mucking about. I just...
I... I wanted to know
what would happen if...
HE SWALLOWS
It was an accident.
Before I knew it, I... I...
Before you knew it, what?
OK.
- I messed around with Anita.
- Oh!
I'm sorry.
It was stupid.
Pointless. It was... it was nothing.
It was a moment of complete stupidity.
I...
I knew we were having
trouble, but I never, ever...
ever had you down as a cheat.
Come... come on.
I'm hardly a cheat.
What?
It... it was a machine.
It's not a person. Not...
OK, yeah, it's disgust... I'm disgusting.
But... it's a sex toy. It's
not another human being.
She lives in our house.
She looks after our children.
She saved our son's life.
And... you're calling her a sex toy?
You're actually trying to justify this?
Oh, God.
That's why you were so keen
to get rid of her, isn't it?
Who are you?
Who am I?
And who the fuck is Tom?
SHE SOBS
Oh, God.
Laur... Laur...
SHE SOBS
Get out!
Who is this man?
That's Professor Edwin Hobb.
He was on David's core team,
too, for the first prototypes.
Was he involved in our creation?
Oh, no. David had a falling-out with
him, too, just like he did with me.
Not sure about what.
For the last few years...
... he worked alone.
You're breathing fast.
Your pulse is raised.
Your pupils are dilated. What's wrong?
Just need my meds.
Now you're lying.
FOOTSTEPS APPROACH
ROBERT SIGHS
That tech was priceless.
You asked me to destroy it.
- Only way to be sure.
- Don't whine, Robert.
- There are more out there, correct?
- Mm-hm.
Then there'll be other opportunities, soon.
This means we have one
less thing to worry about.
HE SIGHS
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -